Guide to the Alex Harris photographs and papers, 1970-2015 RL.10060
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Alex Harris photographs and papers
1970-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Harris, Alex, 1949-
RL.10060
55.6 Linear Feet 86 boxes; 2 oversize folders 667 photographic prints; approximately 16,062 other items
Alex Harris is a documentary photographer, author, and professor emeritus at the Center for Documentary Studies in Durham, North Carolina. The subjects in the over 600 black-and-white and color photographs that span his career include the landscapes and peoples of Alaska, the American South and New Mexico, and Cuba; subjects in other documentary projects include portraits of older reading volunteers and students in Philadelphia, students on strike at Yale University, counter-culture people at a Rainbow Gathering in Arizona, a boy tethered to electronic technology, elderly people living on their own; and the interior of author Reynolds Price's home. The gelatin silver and inkjet prints range in size from 8x10 inch reference prints to 24x36 inch exhibit prints. Harris's professional papers document his collaborations with other photographers and writers on books and exhibitions, including anthropologist Gertrude Duby Blom, naturalist E.O. Wilson, and South African photographers; they also cover his long career at Duke University, as teacher, author, and co-founder of the Center for Documentary Studies and its publication, DoubleTake. In addition to the paper records, there are many recorded oral histories and interviews. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Arrangement
Photographs are organized in project series: The Last and First Eskimos; Southern Color; North Carolina; The Idea of Cuba; Game Boy; May Day, 1970: Yale on Strike; Red White Blue and God Bless You: A Portrait of New Mexico; New Mexico in Black and White; River of Traps (New Mexico); Rainbow Gathering; Philadelphia Experience Corps; Old and On Their Own; and Dream of a House. Harris's professional papers are arranged in these series: Publicity and Audiovisual Materials; Correspondence; Doubletake Files; Project Files; Teaching Materials; and Proof Prints.
Collection Overview
The over 600 black-and-white and color photographs in the collection date from Harris's earliest photographic work as a graduate student at Yale University, to his more recent work documenting the American South. The subjects range widely, and include the landscapes and peoples of Alaska, the American South and New Mexico, and Cuba; they also include portraits of older reading volunteers and students in Philadelphia, students on strike at Yale University, counter-culture people at a Rainbow Gathering in Arizona, a boy going about his day, tethered to electronic technology, elderly people living on their own in central North Carolina, and views of the art-filled interiors of author Reynolds Price's home. The gelatin silver and inkjet prints range in size from 8x10 inch reference prints to 24x36 inch exhibit prints; for large prints there are smaller viewing copies to facilitate research access.
The remaining series house Harris's papers, which document collaborations with other photographers and writers, including Gertrude Duby Blom and E.O. Wilson, and South Africa photographers; they also document his career at Duke University as a teacher, author, and co-founder of the Center for Documentary Studies (CDS) and its serial publication, DoubleTake. The Publicity and Audiovisual Materials Series contains recordings of lectures as well as publicity for exhibits and publications. The Correspondence Series includes not only Harris's exchanges with other photographers, friends, and professionals, but also grant applications, research notes, drafts and proofs, print materials, and some photographs. The DoubleTake files consist mainly of materials generated during the planning stages and early years of the magazine's existence. Materials on Harris's extensive collaborations on other publications, documentary projects, and related exhibitions make up the large Project Files Series, which includes many oral histories and interviews related to his projects, mostly on cassette tapes (use copies must be made for access). The Teaching Materials Series comprises syllabi, student writings and slides, and other materials from classes taught by Harris mainly through the CDS at Duke University. Finally, the Proof Prints Series contains a small number of proof prints related to various projects.
Biographical Note
Alex Harris is a photographer, writer, and teacher. Born in Atlanta, Georgia, he has spent most of his adult life in North Carolina. He has photographed for extended periods in Cuba, the Inuit villages of Alaska, the Hispanic villages of northern New Mexico, and across the American South. He is professor emeritus of the Practice of Public Policy and Documentary Studies at Duke University. At Duke, Harris is a founder of the Center for Documentary Photography (1980), The Center for Documentary Studies (1989), DoubleTake magazine (1995), and The Lewis Hine Documentary Fellows Program (2002) His awards include a John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship in Photography, a Rockefeller Foundation Humanities Fellowship, and a Lyndhurst Prize. Harris's work is represented in major photographic collections, including the J. Paul Getty Museum in Los Angeles, the High Museum of Art in Atlanta, the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York City, the North Carolina Museum of Art in Raleigh, and the San Francisco Museum of Modern Art. His photographs have been exhibited widely, including two solo exhibitions at the International Center of Photography in New York City. As a photographer and editor, Harris has published eighteen books, among them A World Unsuspected: Portraits of Southern Childhood (North Carolina, 1987), River of Traps: A New Mexico Mountain Life (New Mexico, 1990), with William deBuys, which was a finalist for the 1991 Pulitzer Prize in general non-fiction, The Idea of Cuba (New Mexico, 2007), and Why We Are Here: Mobile and the Spirit of a Southern City (Liveright/Norton, 2012), with Edward O. Wilson. Dream of a House: The Passions and Preoccupations of Reynolds Price (GFT/CDS, 2017) and Where We Find Ourselves: The Photographs of Hugh Mangum, 1897–1922, (University of North Carolina Press, CDS, 2019) both with Margaret Sartor.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access note
Due to the vulnerability of very large digital prints, full sets of smaller viewing prints (11x17 inches) are available in the Cuba Auto/Landscapes, Game Boy, and Mobile series, and should be used whenever possible. Please contact the Rubenstein Library for access to the original prints.
Conditions Governing Access note
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Some listening copies are available and are noted in this guide. Use of other materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use this material.
Existence and Location of Copies
Selected images from this collection have been digitized and are available online as part of Duke Digital Collections.
Provenance
The Alex Harris photographs and papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as gifts and purchases from 1992 to 2019.
Related Material
Alex Harris's work in South Africa with fellow documentarians Bruce Payne, Paul Weinberg, Margaret Sartor, and Omar Badsha, and his work with Gertrude Duby Blom in Central America, is represented in the following collections, also held in the Rubenstein Library:
South Africa Documentary Photographs Collection, 1940s-2007 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Gertrude Duby Blom Photographs, 1950s-1980s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Alaska Natives -- Photographs; Authors, American -- Homes and haunts; City and town life -- Alabama; City and town life -- Cuba; Computer games -- Social aspects; Documentary Photography -- Southern States; Documentary Photography -- United States; Duke University -- Faculty; Indigenous peoples -- Portraits; Mexican Americans -- New Mexico -- Portraits; Older people -- North Carolina -- Photographs; Photographers -- United States -- Correspondence; Photography -- Study and teaching; Student protesters -- Photographs; Student strikes -- Photographs; Technology and children -- Photographs; Urban schools -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- Photographs; Alaska -- Photographs; Arizona -- Photographs; Cuba -- Photographs; Havana (Cuba) -- Photographs; Mobile (Ala.) -- Photographs; New Mexico -- Photographs; Southern States -- Photographs; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Digital prints; DVDs; Gelatin silver prints; Inkjet prints; Oral history interviews; Sound recordings; Videocassettes; Harris, Alex, 1949-; Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies. DoubleTake; Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies; Blom, Gertrude Duby -- Interviews; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Price, Reynolds, 1933-2011 -- Homes and haunts; Rainbow Gathering -- Photographs
- The Last and First Eskimos, 1973-1978; 1; 3 boxes; 56 prints
  Scope and Contents
  These black-and-white photographs have as their subjects Eskimos and Inuit elders and their day-to-day lives in small Alaskan communities. The images were taken over the course of multiple trips over a five-year period in the 1970s in villages along the Kobuk River, located above the Arctic Circle, and in fishing villages along the southern coast of the Bering Sea in Alaska. The project provided documentary images for a study conducted by Robert Coles, supported by the non-profit Commonwealth Fund, and published in the book, The Last and First Eskimos (1978). Consists of 50 11x14 inch prints, and six 16x20 inch prints, all in gelatin silver format. Titles assigned by photographer.
  - Caribou Hunting Near Ambler, Alaska, 1973 October (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0057)
  - John Angaiate, Tununak, Alaska, 1976 (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0058)
  - Dancing, Tunanak, Alaska, 1973 Fall (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0059)
  - Charlie Tommy, Nelson Island, Alaska, 1977 July (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0060)
  - Newtok, Alaska, 1976 May (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0061)
  - Andrew Tommy, Checking the nets, Chilugan, Alaska, 1977 July (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0062)
  - Angaiale Home, Tununak, Alaska, 1976 April (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0063)
  - Abandoned Sod House, Yukok, Alaska, 1975 April (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0064)
  - Playing Husky, Shungnak, Alaska, 1973 October (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0065)
  - Tununak, Alaska, 1973 (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0066)
  - Above the Kobuk River, Shungnale, Alaska, 1973 October (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0067)
  - Selawik, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0068)
  - Blowing Snow, Tununak, Alaska, 1975 April (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0069)
  - After Seal Hunting, Tununak, Alaska, 1975 April (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0070)
  - Peter Flynn Family, Tununak, Alaska, 1975 (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0071)
  - Newtok, Alaska, 1977 July (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0072)
  - Blind Man, Selawik, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0073)
  - First Communion Day, Tununak, Alaska, 1978 May (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0074)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1973 September (Box 1, Print RL10060-P-0075)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1973 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0076)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0077)
  - Foothills of the Brooks Range, Near Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0078)
  - Foothills of the Brooks Range, Near Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0079)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0080)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0081)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0082)
  - Dancing, Tununak, Alaska, 1976 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0083)
  - Bethel, Alaska, 1978 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0084)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0085)
  - Visitor from Kobuk, Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0086)
  - Fish Trap, Kasigik (Inuit Lodge), Tununak, Alaska, 1975 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0087)
  - Gathering Firewood near Newtok, Alaska, 1976 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0088)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1973 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0089)
  - Tununak, Alaska, 1976 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0090)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0091)
  - Graveyard, Selawik, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0092)
  - Charlie Tommy, Nelson Island, Alaska, 1977 July (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0093)
  - Above Tununak, Alaska, 1977 July (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0094)
  - Schoolhouse Fire, Selawik, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0095)
  - Wedding, St. Joseph's Catholic Church, Tununak, Alaska, 1976 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0096)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1973 September (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0097)
  - Newtok, Alaska, 1977 July (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0098)
  - Tununak, Alaska, 1977 July (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0099)
  - First Communion Day, Tununak, Alaska, 1978 May (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0100)
  - Pricilla, Tununak, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0101)
  - Simeon Fairbanks Jr. and Charlie Tommy, Newtok, Alaska, 1976 May (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0102)
  - Shungnak, Alaska, 1973 September (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0103)
  - Andrew Tommy, Chilugan, Alaska, 1977 July (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0104)
  - Andrew Tommy, Newtok, Alaska, 1976 (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0105)
  - Charlie Tommy, Newtok, Alaska, 1976 May (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0106)
  - Caribou, Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 2, Print RL10060-P-0107)
  - Selawik Alaska Friends Church, 1974 April (Box 3, Print RL10060-P-0108)
  - Simeon Fairbanks Jr. and Charlie Tommy, Newtok, Alaska, 1976 May (Box 3, Print RL10060-P-0109)
  - Deacons, St. Joseph Catholic Church, Tununak, Alaska, 1976 April (Box 3, Print RL10060-P-0110)
  - Lizzie Lee, Shungnak, Alaska, 1974 April (Box 3, Print RL10060-P-0111)
  - Seal Hunting, Bering Sea at Tununak, Alaska, 1975 April (Box 3, Print RL10060-P-0112)
  - Tununak, Alaska, 1976 (Box 3, Print RL10060-P-0113)
- Southern Color, 1984-1985; 2; 2 boxes; 38 color prints
  Series contains 38 24x30 inch color images taken in Alabama, Georgia, Louisiana, North Carolina, and South Carolina. Photographed from 1984-1985, the subjects are small towns and cities, with their modest houses, gas stations, parking lots, tobacco warehouses, malls, storefronts, usually unpopulated but with old cars and trucks often appearing in the frame. Many of the locations are in Durham, North Carolina; other cities include (but are not limited to) Wilmington, Wake Forest, and Norlina, North Carolina; Birmingham, Alabama; Monroe, Bastrop, and Raysville, Louisiana; Summerton, St. Helena's Island, and Charleston, South Carolina; and Hinesville, Sunbury, and Stone Mountain, Georgia. The project was funded by an award from the Lyndhurst Foundation. Titles assigned by photographer.
  - Howard Ford, Durham, North Carolina, 1985 February (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0114)
  - Summerton, South Carolina, 1985 March 27 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0115)
  - Peggy's Cake Shop, West Monroe, Louisiana, 1985 May (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0116)
  - Phillip Hanes House, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, 1985 January 10 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0117)
  - Delhi, Louisiana, 1985 May 3 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0118)
  - Jack Campbell's House, Sunbury, Georgia, 1985 March 25 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0119)
  - Birmingham, Alabama, 1985 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0120)
  - Wig Shop, Charleston, South Carolina, 1984 October 2 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0121)
  - Irene's Store, Rayville, Louisiana, 1985 April 25 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0122)
  - Hattadare Nation, Bunnlevel, North Carolina, 1985 March 22 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0123)
  - Pretty Boy's Playhouse, Monroe, Louisiana, 1985 May 15 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0124)
  - American Tobacco, Durham, North Carolina, 1985 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0125)
  - Star Warehouse, Riggsbee Street, Durham, North Carolina, 1985 September (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0126)
  - Sunset Cab Company, Desiard Street, Monroe, Louisiana, 1985 May 5 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0127)
  - Dixie Dream Motel, Dillon, North Carolina, 1985 March 27 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0128)
  - Chain Saw Repair, North Carolina, 1985 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0129)
  - Car Land, Monroe, Louisiana, 1985 May 1 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0130)
  - Alonzo Roberson's House, Williamston, North Carolina, 1984 October 29 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0131)
  - Norlina, North Carolina, 1985 March 29 (Box 4, Print RL10060-P-0132)
  - Scotch Hall, Merry Hill, North Carolina, 1984 November 13 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0133)
  - I and J Auto Repair Services, after Hurricane Diana, Wilmington, North Carolina, 1984 September 16 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0134)
  - Wake Forest, North Carolina, 1984 October 27 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0135)
  - Fripp Plantation, St. Helena Island, South Carolina, 1985 January 21 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0136)
  - Dawn, Hinesville, Georgia, 1985 March 27 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0137)
  - Roper House, Charleston, South Carolina, 1984 November 29 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0138)
  - North Mangum and Corporation Streets, Durham, North Carolina, 1984 September 23 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0139)
  - Baskin, Louisiana, 1985 May 17 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0140)
  - Rutledge and Calhoun Streets, Charleston, North Carolina, 1984 October 2 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0141)
  - Great American Indian Leaders, South Square Mall, Durham, North Carolina, 1984 May (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0142)
  - Totally Free Checking, Home Federal Savings and Loan, Charleston, South Carolina, 1984 October 4 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0143)
  - Judy Osborne, Sunbury, Georgia, 1985 March 24 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0144)
  - Stone Mountain, Georgia, 1984 December 23 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0145)
  - Broadway Yellow Cab, Durham, North Carolina, 1985 February 23 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0146)
  - Bayou Gin Company, Stearlington, Louisiana, 1985 May 6 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0147)
  - Route 137 between Bastrop and Oak Ridge, Louisiana, 1985 May 8 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0148)
  - Salemburg, North Carolina, 1985 March 14 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0149)
  - Durham, North Carolina, 1985 February (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0150)
  - Magnolia Shopping Center, Bastrop, Louisiana, 1985 May 8 (Box 5, Print RL10060-P-0151)
- North Carolina, 1971-1972; 3; 3 boxes, 1 oversize folder; 57 prints
  Representing some of Harris's earliest work, this project was an initiative of the Institute of Policy Sciences and Public Affairs at Duke University and started as a photographic study of substandard housing and living conditions in the state. Featured are portraits of North Carolinians and scenes from rural locations from counties in the eastern, central and western regions. There are portraits of people of all ages and races, and are shown in front of their dwellings; working, chiefly at agricultural tasks; and relaxing by pitching horseshoes. A number of them are of migrant workers. Fifty-six black-and-white 17x22 inch digital prints.
  In 1972, a selection of these photographs was exhibited at University of North Carolina Symposium on the South, "The Mind of the South and The Southern Soul" as well as at the Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art. In 1978, ten of these photographs were also published in I Shall Save One Land Unvisited by Jonathan Williams, and were part of a traveling exhibition opening at the Corcoran that same year.
  Eleven other exhibit prints, printed in 2015 for the exhibition "Where We Live: A North Carolina Portrait," are housed in this collection.
  Titles assigned by photographer.
  - Hickory Nut Gap, North Carolina, cabin interior, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0001)
  - Jones County, North Carolina, 1972 June (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0002)
  - Migrant crew boss, Mount Olive, North Carolina, 1972 May (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0003)
  - Halifax County, North Carolina, woman in curlers, 1971 December (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0004)
  - Princeville, North Carolina, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0005)
  - Hickory Nut Gap, North Carolina, house with gospel and Coca Cola sign, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0006)
  - Princeville, North Carolina, 1972 January (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0007)
  - Wolf Mountain, Route 281, Western North Carolina, 1971 (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0008)
  - Transylvania County, North Carolina, 1971 October (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0009)
  - Halifax County, North Carolina, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0010)
  - Halifax County, North Carolina, woman in her bedroom, 1971 December (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0011)
  - Halifax County, North Carolina, farmer and wife, 1971 December (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0012)
  - Roaring Gap, North Carolina, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0013)
  - Jones County, North Carolina, 1972 July (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0014)
  - Halifax County, North Carolina, cotton farm, 1971 December (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0015)
  - Western North Carolina, woman holding baby, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0016)
  - Hickory Nut Gap, North Carolina, woman and her house, 1971 November (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0017)
  - Western North Carolina, Route 281, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0018)
  - Jackson City, North Carolina, 1971 October (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0019)
  - Ocean Baptism, Currituck County, 1972 July (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0020)
  - Wolf Mountain, North Carolina, 1971 October (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0021)
  - Hickory Nut Gap, North Carolina, cars, 1971 November (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0022)
  - Princeville, North Carolina, 1972 February (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0023)
  - Migrant worker, Carteret County, North Carolina, 1972 June (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0024)
  - Transylvania County, North Carolina, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0025)
  - Western North Carolina, man sleeping in front of house, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0026)
  - Western North Carolina, warning sign, 1972 Summer (Box 6, Print RL10060-P-0027)
  - Jones County, North Carolina, woman in front of her house (2), 1972 Summer (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0028)
  - Potato sorting facility, Carteret County, North Carolina, hand with potato, 1972 June (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0029)
  - Tarboro, North Carolina, 1972 February (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0030)
  - Hickory Nut Gap, North Carolina, barking dog, 1972 June (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0031)
  - Sampson County, North Carolina, 1972 July (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0032)
  - Eastern North Carolina, man and woman, 1972 Summer (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0033)
  - Currituck County, North Carolina, 1971 December (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0034)
  - Pender County, North Carolina, woman and cat in front of her store, 1972 Summer (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0035)
  - Carteret County, North Carolina, children on trampoline in front of trailer, 1972 June (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0036)
  - Western North Carolina, basketball hoop in front of cemetery, 1972 June (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0037)
  - Migrant workers, Carteret County, North Carolina, 1972 June (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0038)
  - Migrant workers, Camden, North Carolina, throwing horseshoes, 1972 Summer (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0039)
  - Western North Carolina, woman and dogs, 1971 Summer (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0040)
  - Highway 10, Western North Carolina, 1971 October (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0041)
  - Jackson County, North Carolina, 1971 October (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0042)
  - Post office, Western North Carolina, 1971 October (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0043)
  - Auction, Sampson County, North Carolina, 1972 Summer (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0044)
  - Eastern North Carolina, houses along street, 1972 Summer (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0045)
  - Tarboro, North Carolina, 1972 January (Box 7, Print RL10060-P-0046)